<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>https://mk2112.github.io</link>
    <description>Posts from my blog</description>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>An Evolution of Wireless Channel Equalization</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/equalizers.html</link>
      <description>Wireless signals drive modern tech, but they are error-prone and easily distorted.
                This post explores how wireless signal correction has evolved, from classic methods like Zero-Forcing and MMSE to
                adaptive algorithms like LMS and RLS, and finally to upcoming AI-powered equalization techniques for
                large-scale, accurate signal restoration.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 13:38:01 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/equalizers.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diffusion Language Models</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/diffusion-lm.html</link>
      <description>Diffusion drives the field of generative modeling, but its application to language tasks was limited. That is, until recently.
                Diffusion language models emerge as a promising alternative to pre-existing language modeling paradigms, generating text as a whole rather than autoregressively,
                thus saving time. We explore how diffusion language models work, their potential to advance text generation, and their shortcomings.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/diffusion-lm.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Systematic Approach to Digital Self-Sovereignty</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/digital-self-sovereignty.html</link>
      <description>Privacy means negotiation between security and usability. Owning your data increasingly becomes a focus again and techniques
                that layer protections can actively help in reducing your exposure without complicating life. To achieve this, we break
                privacy down to its ingredients, and provide actionable solutions that help reducing your digital footprint.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 21:07:27 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/digital-self-sovereignty.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Data Subsets, from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/subsets-from-scratch.html</link>
      <description>Increasingly, research and academia find themselves hindered by the breathtaking demands for resources required to keep up with
                industrial, closed AI research.
                Let's discuss data subset distillation and efficient approaches to distill data subsets even in resource-constrained settings.
                Applying these distillations can enable orders of magnitude faster training times while still majorly retaining performance, 
                saving time, energy, money, and help leveling the playing field.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 23:09:33 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/subsets-from-scratch.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing 64-Bit Linux on a 32-Bit EFI Device</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/64-bit-linux-on-32-bit-efi.html</link>
      <description>Modern computing can often present calculated constraints. The ASUS X205TA, a machine architecturally capable 
                of 64-bit computing, is restricted to 32-bit operation by its EFI. This is a story of circumvention, understanding
                system boundaries and methodically dismantling them.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 02:35:09 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/64-bit-linux-on-32-bit-efi.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DreamerV2 and DreamerV3, Explained</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/dreamer.html</link>
      <description>Developing intelligent systems for robustly perceiving, exploring, and attaining incrementally complex insights remains a persistent challenge in the field.
                The Dreamer algorithm addresses this by employing latent imagination and reinforcement learning, enabling the development of effective policies for various
                tasks in different environments.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 15:54:46 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/dreamer.html</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long Short-Term Memory</title>
      <link>https://mk2112.github.io/blog/lstm.html</link>
      <description>Long Short-Term Memory is a recurrent neural network type for learning long-term dependencies. This was hard to achieve, especially due to the vanishing
                gradient problem experienced up until that point. LSTM was the first in overcoming this issue, and it proved foundational for many subsequent advances
                in deep learning.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 03:57:35 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://mk2112.github.io/blog/lstm.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
